30 chapter 31 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna chapter 31 A Humbug My master was not immediately
suited, but in a few days my new groom came. He was tall, good-looking fellow
enough; but if ever there was a humbug in the shape of a groom Alfred Smirk was
the man. He was very civil to me, and
never used me ill; in fact, he did a great deal of stroking and patting when his
master was there to see it. He always brushed my man and tail with water and
my Hooves with oil before he brought me to the door, to make me look smart; but as
to cleaning my feet or looking to my shoes, or grooming me thoroughly, he
thought no more of that than if I had been a cow. He left my bit rusty, my
saddle damp, and my crer stiff. Alfred Smirk considered himself
very handsome; he spent a great deal of time about his hair, whiskers and necktie,
before a little Looking Glass in the harness room When his master was
speaking to him it was always, “Yes, sir; yes, sir”— ”—touching his hat at every word;
and everyone thought he was was a very nice young man and that Mr. Barry was
very fortunate to meet with him. I should say he was the laziest, most
conceited fellow I ever came near. Of course, it was a great thing not
to be ill-used, but then a horse wants more than that. I had a loose box, and
might have been very comfortable if he had not been too indolent to clean it
out. He never took all the straw away, and the smell from what lay underneath was
very bad and the strong vapors that rose made my eyes smart and inflame, and I did
not feel the same appetite for my food. One day his master came in and said,
“Alfred, the stable smells rather strong; should not you give that stall a good
scrub and throw down plenty of water?” “Well, sir,” he said, touching his cap,
“I'll do so if you please, sir; but it is rather dangerous, sir, throwing down water
in a horse's box; they are very apt to
take C sir. I should not like to do him
an injury, but I'll do it if you please, sir.” “Well,” said his master, “I should not
like him to take cold; but I don't like the smell of the stable. Do you think the
drains are all right?” “Well, sir, now you mention it, I
think the drain does sometimes send back a smell; there may be something wrong,
sir.” “Then send for the brick layer and have it seen to,” said his master. “Yes, sir, I
will.” The brick brick layer came and pulled up a great many bricks, but found
nothing a miss so he put down some lime and charged the master of five shillings,
and the smell in my box was as bad as
ever. But that was not all: standing as I did on a quantity of moist straw my feet
grew unhealthy and tender, and a master used to say: “I don't know what is the
matter with this horse; he goes very fumble footed I am sometimes afraid he will
stumble.” “Yes, sir,” said Alfred, “I have noticed the same myself, when I exercised
him.” Now the fact was that he hardly ever did exercise me, and when the master was
busy I often stood for days together without stretching my legs at all, and
yet being fed just as high as if I were at hard work. This often disordered my
health, and made me sometimes heavy and dull, but more often restless and
feverish. He never even gave me a meal of green food or a brand mesh which would
have cooled me, for he was altogether as ignorant as he was conceited; and then,
instead of exercise or change of food, I had to take horse balls and drafts which
besides the nuisance of having them poured down my throat, used to make me feel ill and
uncomfortable. One day my feet were so tender that, trotting over some fresh
stones with my master on my back, I made two such serious stumbles that, as he
came down lown into the city, he stopped at the farers and asked him to see what
was the matter with him The man took up my feet one by one and examined them;
then standing up and dusting his hands one against the other, he said: “Your horse
has got the 'thrush', and badly, too; his feet are very tender; it is fortunate
that he has not been down. I wonder your groom has not seen to it before. This is
the sort of thing we find in foul stables, where the litter is never
properly cleaned out. If you will send him here tomorrow I will attend to the
hoof, and I will direct man how to apply the linament which I will give
him.” The next day I had my feet thoroughly cleaned and stuffed with toe
soaked in some strong lotion; and an unpleasant business it
was. The fer ordered all the litter to be
taken out of my box day by day, and the
floor kept very clean. Then I was to have brand meshes a little green food, and not
so much corn, till my feet were well again. With this treatment I soon
regained my spirits; but Mr. Barry was so much disgusted at being twice deceived
by his grooms that he determined to give up keeping a horse, and to hire when he
wanted one. I was therefore kept till my feet were quite sound, and was then sold
again end of chapter 31 end of part